

MIRIAM BADE Software Engineer

- ♥ Great Falls, MT
- **** +14064755206

☑yukinomiriam@gmail.com

miriambade.com

Introduction

Stay-at-home mom of a 10 month old baby girl looking forward to go back to the working life as a Software Developer.

I have 9 years of experience working in Java Enterprise Projects performing activities of: analysis, development, testing, deployment, and software debugging as well as production support.

Skills

Back end development

Use of Java, XML, C#, Spring, Struts, Hibernate, Abator, EJB, SVN, SOAP., Mayen.

Front end development

Use of jQuery, AJAX, JSON, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JSP, JSF.

Databases

Oracle, MySQL, SQL, JDBC, PL/SQL.

Production Support

Meetings with the user in case of production issues, tracking of reported issues using JIRA. Development of enhancements and defects fixes per release.

Others

DevOps, SDLC, Agile, UML, BPMN, Storyboarding,

Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer

Work experience

Solutions Engineer

Deloitte LLP

Solutions Engineer-Bismarck, ND

- Collaborated in a team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives in a measured and open manner.
- Performed 4 onsite training sessions for client-side developers to maximize productivity.
- Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of 3 enhancements.
- Coordinated with offshore team to confirm, develop and test requirements and defects on daily calls.
- Participated in requirements gathering and design development meetings.
- Performed troubleshooting, diagnostics and analysis to uncover root malfunctions solving at least 1 issue per day.
- Reviewed code and debugged errors to improve performance.
- Consistently met deadlines and requirements for all production work orders.
- Completed at least 3 low-level defects for every biweekly release and 2 high-level defects and enhancements per monthly release.
- Technologies Used:
- JAVA 7, EJB, WEBSPHERE, JSP, JAVASCRIPT, XML, ORACLE 12C, PL/SQL, SVN, JIRA

IT Consultant

2012-12 - 2016-05

2016-06 - 2017-09

Deloitte Consulting Mexico

IT Consultant Helena, MT

- Collaborated in a team-based, Agile environment to accomplish objectives in a measured and open manner.
- Performed production support activities resolving at least 3 issues per week. This included the analysis and resolution of production issues for two Web Enterprise Applications.
- Resolved production issues in less than 24 hours of their occurrence.
- Delivered 14 assigned enhancements and defects on-time and to a high level of quality during the construction phase for the new release. This included the steps of analysis, design, development and unit testing.
- Communicated daily progress to track lead indicating progress made against assignments.
- Technologies Used:
- JAVA 6, EJB, WEBSPHERE, JSP, JAVASCRIPT, XML, ORACLE 10G, PL/SQL, SVN ,JIRA

Java Developer

2012-04 - 2012-11

Quality & Knowledge on IT Services - Mexico City, Mexico

- Designed and updated layouts to meet usability and performance requirements.
- Consulted with customers to gather requirements and discuss design choices.
- Developed designs to meet specific requirements such as quick-loading sites with layouts.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Technologies Used:
- JAVA 5, MY FACES, FACELETS, TOMAHAWK, SPRING 3.0, HIBERNATE 3.1, ORACLE 10G, MAVEN 2, SVN

Java Developer

2009-08 - 2012-03

LightSoft - Mexico City, Mexico

- Developed a robust Java code for Web applications.
- Developed Java code for 4 Blackberry applications.
- Collaborated with clients from concept through final delivery of a requirement.
- Directed onsite training for business users.
- Technologies Used:
- JAVA 6, BLACKBERRY API, JSON, SPRING 2.5, MY SQL 5.5, APACHE TOMCAT, ORACLE 10G, STRUTS 2, AVATOR, JBOSS 5

Junior Java Developer

2008-03 - 2009-07

iSmarts - Mexico City, Mexico

- Developed requirements along with senior developers.
- Provided documentation for new requirements.
- Documented customer requirements and project plans.
- Created documentation using UML and BPMN.
- Technologies Used:

Languages

- English (Professional)
- Spanish (Native)

Interests

- Photography
- Graphic Design
- Cooking

JAVA 5, MY FACES, TOMAHAWK, APACHE TOMCAT, ORACLE 10G, UML, BPMN, SVN

Side Projects

2018-09 - Present

Miriam Bade Photography

Owner, Photographer, Developer. I've created www.miriambade.com as a way to publish my photographies without depending on the approval of a stock website to post my photos on their websites.

This project has been also helping me to remember and to learn new Java technologies due to currently I am trying to go back to the working force as a Java Developer.

Technologies used:

 JAVA 8, HIBERNATE 4.3, SPRING 4.0, JSP, BOOTSTRAP 4, TOMCAT 9, MY SQL 8, GIT, MAVEN 4.

The code is stored in my git repository: https://github.com/yukinomiriam/mbPhotography_Spring

Education

B.Sc Computer Science and Engineering

Universidad ETAC - Mexico City, Mexico

2003 - 2006